<language>
  <lang>
    <dialogs>
      <dialog>
        <int>1</int>
        <en>I hope a scrawny kid like you isn't all that is standing between us and Cthulu's Eye.</en>
        <ja></ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>2</int>
        <en>Look at that shoddy armor you're wearing. Better buy some more healing potions.</en>
        <ja></ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>3</int>
        <en>I feel like an evil presence is watching me.</en>
        <ja>邪悪な存在が私を見ている気がします。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>4</int>
        <en>Sword beats paper! Get one today.</en>
        <ja>剣はペンより強し。ということでお一つ買って行って下さい。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>5</int>
        <en>You want apples? You want carrots? You want pineapples? We got torches.</en>
        <ja>リンゴ？ニンジン？パイナップル？トーチならあるんですが。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>6</int>
        <en>Lovely morning, wouldn't you say? Was there something you needed?</en>
        <ja>いやぁ、良い朝ですね。何かご入用ですか？</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>7</int>
        <en>Night will be upon us soon, friend. Make your choices while you can.</en>
        <ja>もうすぐ日が暮れますね。何を買っていきますか？</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>8</int>
        <en>You have no idea how much Dirt Blocks sell for overseas.</en>
        <ja>海外では土のブロックも売り物になるんですよ。いくらで売れると思います？</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>9</int>
        <en>Ah, they will tell tales of {Player} some day... good ones I'm sure.</en>
        <ja>いつか皆が{Player}の物語を語るでしょうね。勇者の物語を。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>10</int>
        <en>Check out my dirt blocks, they are extra dirty.</en>
        <ja>私の周りの土のブロックを見てください。どうも汚染されてるようです。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>11</int>
        <en>Boy, that sun is hot! I do have some perfectly ventilated armor.</en>
        <ja>今日は日差しが強いですね。私は通気性の良い防具も扱ってますよ。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>12</int>
        <en>The sun is high, but my prices are not.</en>
        <ja>陽が高いですねぇ。しかしウチの値段は違いますよ。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>13</int>
        <en>Oh, great. I can hear {Mechanic} and {Nurse} arguing from here.</en>
        <ja>{Mechanic}と{Nurse}が何か議論しているのが聞こえますね。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>14</int>
        <en>Have you seen Chith...Shith.. Chat... The big eye?</en>
        <ja>あなたはキトゥ…クトゥ…。…えーと、何とかの目玉を見たことがありますか？</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>15</int>
        <en>Hey, this house is secure, right? Right? {Player}?</en>
        <ja>この家は安全ですよね？{Player}？</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>16</int>
        <en>Not even a blood moon can stop capitalism. Let's do some business.</en>
        <ja>ブラッドムーンですら資本主義は止められませんよ。さぁ、ビジネスをしましょう。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>17</int>
        <en>Keep your eye on the prize, buy a lense!</en>
        <ja>掘り出し物がありますよ。レンズなんかどうです？</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>18</int>
        <en>Kosh, kapleck Mog. Oh sorry, that's klingon for 'Buy something or die.'</en>
        <ja>Kosh, kapleck Mog. …あぁ、すいません。今のはクリンゴン語で「買うか死ぬか」という意味です。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>19</int>
        <en>{Player} is it? I've heard good things, friend!</en>
        <ja>{Player}さんですか？噂は聞いてますよ！</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>20</int>
        <en>I hear there's a secret treasure... oh never mind.</en>
        <ja>秘密の宝があると聞いたんですが…いや、忘れてください。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>21</int>
        <en>Angel Statue you say? I'm sorry, I'm not a junk dealer.</en>
        <ja>天使の石像ですって？申し訳ないですが、私はジャンク屋ではないので。</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>22</int>
        <en>The last guy who was here left me some junk... er I mean... treasures!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>23</int>
        <en>I wonder if the moon is made of cheese...huh, what? Oh yes, buy something!</en>
        <ja>もし月がチーズで出来ていたら…。え、はい？何か買いますか？</ja>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>24</int>
        <en>Did you say gold?  I'll take that off of ya.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>25</int>
        <en>You better not get blood on me.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>26</int>
        <en>Hurry up and stop bleeding.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>27</int>
        <en>If you're going to die, do it outside.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>28</int>
        <en>What is that supposed to mean?!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>29</int>
        <en>I don't think I like your tone.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>30</int>
        <en>Why are you even here? If you aren't bleeding, you don't need to be here. Get out.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>31</int>
        <en>WHAT?!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>32</int>
        <en>Have you seen that old man pacing around the dungeon? He looks troubled.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>33</int>
        <en>I wish {Demolitionist} would be more careful.  I'm getting tired of having to sew his limbs back on every day.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>34</int>
        <en>Hey, has {Arms Dealer} mentioned needing to go to the doctor for any reason? Just wondering.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>35</int>
        <en>I need to have a serious talk with {Guide}. How many times a week can you come in with severe lava burns?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>36</int>
        <en>I think you look better this way.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>37</int>
        <en>Eww... What happened to your face?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>38</int>
        <en>MY GOODNESS! I'm good, but I'm not THAT good.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>39</int>
        <en>Dear friends we are gathered here today to bid farewell... Oh, you'll be fine.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>40</int>
        <en>You left your arm over there. Let me get that for you...</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>41</int>
        <en>Quit being such a baby! I've seen worse.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>42</int>
        <en>That's gonna need stitches!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>43</int>
        <en>Trouble with those bullies again?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>44</int>
        <en>Hold on, I've got some cartoon bandages around here somewhere.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>45</int>
        <en>Walk it off, {Player}, you'll be fine. Sheesh.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>46</int>
        <en>Does it hurt when you do that? Don't do that.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>47</int>
        <en>You look half digested. Have you been chasing slimes again?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>48</int>
        <en>Turn your head and cough.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>49</int>
        <en>That's not the biggest I've ever seen... Yes, I've seen bigger wounds for sure.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>50</int>
        <en>Would you like a lollipop?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>51</int>
        <en>Show me where it hurts.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>52</int>
        <en>I'm sorry, but you can't afford me.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>53</int>
        <en>I'm gonna need more gold than that.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>54</int>
        <en>I don't work for free you know.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>55</int>
        <en>I don't give happy endings.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>56</int>
        <en>I can't do anymore for you without plastic surgery.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>57</int>
        <en>Quit wasting my time.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>58</int>
        <en>I heard there is a doll that looks very similar to {Guide} somewhere in the underworld.  I'd like to put a few rounds in it.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>59</int>
        <en>Make it quick! I've got a date with {Nurse} in an hour.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>60</int>
        <en>I want what {Nurse} is sellin'. What do you mean, she doesn't sell anything?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>61</int>
        <en>{Dryad} is a looker.  Too bad she's such a prude.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>62</int>
        <en>Don't bother with {Demolitionist}, I've got all you need right here.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>63</int>
        <en>What's {Demolitionist}'s problem? Does he even realize we sell completely different stuff?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>64</int>
        <en>Man, it's a good night not to talk to anybody, don't you think, {Player}?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>65</int>
        <en>I love nights like tonight.  There is never a shortage of things to kill!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>66</int>
        <en>I see you're eyeballin' the Minishark.. You really don't want to know how it was made.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>67</int>
        <en>Hey, this ain't a movie, pal. Ammo is extra.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>68</int>
        <en>Keep your hands off my gun, buddy!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>69</int>
        <en>Have you tried using purification powder on the ebonstone of the corruption?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>70</int>
        <en>I wish {Arms Dealer} would stop flirting with me. Doesn't he realize I'm 500 years old?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>71</int>
        <en>Why does {Merchant} keep trying to sell me an angel statues? Everyone knows that they don't do anything.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>72</int>
        <en>Have you seen the old man walking around the dungeon? He doesn't look well at all...</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>73</int>
        <en>I sell what I want! If you don't like it, too bad.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>74</int>
        <en>Why do you have to be so confrontational during a time like this?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>75</int>
        <en>I don't want you to buy my stuff. I want you to want to buy my stuff, ok?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>76</int>
        <en>Dude, is it just me or is there like a million zombies out tonight?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>77</int>
        <en>You must cleanse the world of this corruption.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>78</int>
        <en>Be safe; Terraria needs you!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>79</int>
        <en>The sands of time are flowing. And well, you are not aging very gracefully.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>80</int>
        <en>What's this about me having more 'bark' than bite?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>81</int>
        <en>So two goblins walk into a bar, and one says to the other, 'Want to get a Goblet of beer?!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>82</int>
        <en>I cannot let you enter until you free me of my curse.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>83</int>
        <en>Come back at night if you wish to enter.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>84</int>
        <en>My master cannot be summoned under the light of day.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>85</int>
        <en>You are far too weak to defeat my curse.  Come back when you aren't so worthless.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>86</int>
        <en>You pathetic fool.  You cannot hope to face my master as you are now.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>87</int>
        <en>I hope you have like six friends standing around behind you.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>88</int>
        <en>Please, no, stranger. You'll only get yourself killed.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>89</int>
        <en>You just might be strong enough to free me from my curse...</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>90</int>
        <en>Stranger, do you possess the strength to defeat my master?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>91</int>
        <en>Please! Battle my captor and free me! I beg you!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>92</int>
        <en>Defeat my master, and I will grant you passage into the Dungeon.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>93</int>
        <en>Trying to get past that ebonrock, eh?  Why not introduce it to one of these explosives!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>94</int>
        <en>Hey, have you seen a clown around?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>95</int>
        <en>There was a bomb sitting right here, and now I can't seem to find it...</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>96</int>
        <en>I've got something for them zombies alright!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>97</int>
        <en>Even {Arms Dealer} wants what I'm selling!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>98</int>
        <en>Would you rather have a bullet hole or a grenade hole? That's what I thought.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>99</int>
        <en>I'm sure {Nurse} will help if you accidentally lose a limb to these.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>100</int>
        <en>Why purify the world when you can just blow it up?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>101</int>
        <en>If you throw this one in the bathtub and close all the windows, it'll clear your sinuses and pop your ears!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>102</int>
        <en>Wanna play Fuse Chicken?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>103</int>
        <en>Hey, could you sign this Griefing Waiver?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>104</int>
        <en>NO SMOKING IN HERE!!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>105</int>
        <en>Explosives are da' bomb these days.  Buy some now!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>106</int>
        <en>It's a good day to die!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>107</int>
        <en>I wonder what happens if I... (BOOM!)... Oh, sorry, did you need that leg?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>108</int>
        <en>Dynamite, my own special cure-all for what ails ya.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>109</int>
        <en>Check out my goods; they have explosive prices!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>110</int>
        <en>I keep having vague memories of tying up a woman and throwing her in a dungeon.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>111</int>
        <en>... we have a problem! Its a blood moon out there!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>112</int>
        <en>T'were I younger, I would ask {Nurse} out. I used to be quite the lady killer.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>113</int>
        <en>That Red Hat of yours looks familiar...</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>114</int>
        <en>Thanks again for freeing me from my curse. Felt like something jumped up and bit me.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>115</int>
        <en>Mama always said I would make a great tailor.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>116</int>
        <en>Life's like a box of clothes; you never know what you are gonna wear!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>117</int>
        <en>Of course embroidery is hard! If it wasn't hard, no one would do it! That's what makes it great.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>118</int>
        <en>I know everything they is to know about the clothierin' business.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>119</int>
        <en>Being cursed was lonely, so I once made a friend out of leather. I named him Wilson.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>120</int>
        <en>Thank you for freeing me, human.  I was tied up and left here by the other goblins.  You could say that we didn't get along very well.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>121</int>
        <en>I can't believe they tied me up and left me here just for pointing out that they weren't going east!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>122</int>
        <en>Now that I'm an outcast, can I throw away the spiked balls? My pockets hurt.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>123</int>
        <en>Looking for a gadgets expert? I'm your goblin!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>124</int>
        <en>Thanks for your help. Now, I have to finish pacing around aimlessly here. I'm sure we'll meet again.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>125</int>
        <en>I thought you'd be taller.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>126</int>
        <en>Hey...what's {Mechanic} up to? Have you...have you talked to her, by chance?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>127</int>
        <en>Hey, does your hat need a motor? I think I have a motor that would fit exactly in that hat.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>128</int>
        <en>Yo, I heard you like rockets and running boots, so I put some rockets in your running boots.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>129</int>
        <en>Silence is golden. Duct tape is silver.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>130</int>
        <en>YES, gold is stronger than iron. What are they teaching these humans nowadays?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>131</int>
        <en>You know, that mining helmet-flipper combination was a much better idea on paper.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>132</int>
        <en>Goblins are surprisingly easy to anger. In fact, they could start a war over cloth!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>133</int>
        <en>To be honest, most goblins aren't exactly rocket scientists. Well, some are.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>134</int>
        <en>Do you know why we all carry around these spiked balls? Because I don't.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>135</int>
        <en>I just finished my newest creation! This version doesn't explode violently if you breathe on it too hard.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>136</int>
        <en>Goblin thieves aren't very good at their job. They can't even steal from an unlocked chest!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>137</int>
        <en>Thanks for saving me, friend!  This bondage was starting to chafe.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>138</int>
        <en>Ohh, my hero!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>139</int>
        <en>Oh, how heroic! Thank you for saving me, young lady!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>140</int>
        <en>Oh, how heroic! Thank you for saving me, young man!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>141</int>
        <en>Now that we know each other, I can move in with you, right?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>142</int>
        <en>Well, hi there, {Guide}! What can I do for you today?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>143</int>
        <en>Well, hi there, {Demolitionist}! What can I do for you today?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>144</int>
        <en>Well, hi there, {Goblin}! What can I do for you today?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>145</int>
        <en>Well, hi there, {Nurse}! What can I do for you today?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>146</int>
        <en>Well, hi there, {Mechanic}! What can I do for you today?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>147</int>
        <en>Well, hi there, {Dryad}! What can I do for you today?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>148</int>
        <en>Want me to pull a coin from behind your ear? No? Ok.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>149</int>
        <en>Do you want some magic candy? No? Ok.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>150</int>
        <en>I make a rather enchanting hot chocolate if you'd be inter...No? Ok.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>151</int>
        <en>Are you here for a peek at my crystal ball?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>152</int>
        <en>Ever wanted an enchanted ring that turns rocks into slimes? Well neither did I.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>153</int>
        <en>Someone once told me friendship is magic. That's ridiculous. You can't turn people into frogs with friendship.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>154</int>
        <en>I can see your future now... You will buy a lot of items from me!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>155</int>
        <en>I once tried to bring an Angel Statue to life. It didn't do anything.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>156</int>
        <en>Thanks!  It was just a matter of time before I ended up like the rest of the skeletons down here.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>157</int>
        <en>Hey, watch where you're going! I was over there a little while ago!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>158</int>
        <en>Hold on, I've almost got wifi going down here.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>159</int>
        <en>But I was almost done putting blinking lights up here!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>160</int>
        <en>DON'T MOVE. I DROPPED MY CONTACT.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>161</int>
        <en>All I want is for the switch to make the... What?!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>162</int>
        <en>Oh, let me guess. Didn't buy enough wire. Idiot.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>163</int>
        <en>Just-could you just... Please? Ok? Ok. Ugh.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>164</int>
        <en>I don't appreciate the way you're looking at me. I am WORKING right now.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>165</int>
        <en>Hey {Player}, did you just come from {Goblin}'s? Did he say anything about me by chance?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>166</int>
        <en>{Arms Dealer} keeps talking about pressing my pressure plate. I told him it was for stepping on.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>167</int>
        <en>Always buy more wire than you need!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>168</int>
        <en>Did you make sure your device was plugged in?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>169</int>
        <en>Oh, you know what this house needs? More blinking lights.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>170</int>
        <en>You can tell a Blood Moon is out when the sky turns red. There is something about it that causes monsters to swarm.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>171</int>
        <en>Hey, buddy, do you know where any deathweed is? Oh, no reason; just wondering, is all.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>172</int>
        <en>If you were to look up, you'd see that the moon is red right now.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>173</int>
        <en>You should stay indoors at night. It is very dangerous to be wandering around in the dark.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>174</int>
        <en>Greetings, {Player}. Is there something I can help you with?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>175</int>
        <en>I am here to give you advice on what to do next.  It is recommended that you talk with me anytime you get stuck.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>176</int>
        <en>They say there is a person who will tell you how to survive in this land... oh wait. That's me.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>177</int>
        <en>You can use your pickaxe to dig through dirt, and your axe to chop down trees. Just place your cursor over the tile and click!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>178</int>
        <en>If you want to survive, you will need to create weapons and shelter. Start by chopping down trees and gathering wood.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>179</int>
        <en>Press ESC to access your crafting menu. When you have enough wood, create a workbench. This will allow you to create more complicated things, as long as you are standing close to it.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>180</int>
        <en>You can build a shelter by placing wood or other blocks in the world. Don't forget to create and place walls.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>181</int>
        <en>Once you have a wooden sword, you might try to gather some gel from the slimes. Combine wood and gel to make a torch!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>182</int>
        <en>To interact with backgrounds and placed objects, use a hammer!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>183</int>
        <en>You should do some mining to find metal ore. You can craft very useful things with it.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>184</int>
        <en>Now that you have some ore, you will need to turn it into a bar in order to make items with it. This requires a furnace!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>185</int>
        <en>You can create a furnace out of torches, wood, and stone. Make sure you are standing near a work bench.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>186</int>
        <en>You will need an anvil to make most things out of metal bars.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>187</int>
        <en>Anvils can be crafted out of iron, or purchased from a merchant.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>188</int>
        <en>Underground are crystal hearts that can be used to increase your max life. You will need a hammer to obtain them.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>189</int>
        <en>If you gather 10 fallen stars, they can be combined to create an item that will increase your magic capacity.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>190</int>
        <en>Stars fall all over the world at night. They can be used for all sorts of usefull things. If you see one, be sure to grab it because they disappear after sunrise.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>191</int>
        <en>There are many different ways you can attract people to move in to our town. They will of course need a home to live in.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>192</int>
        <en>In order for a room to be considered a home, it needs to have a door, chair, table, and a light source.  Make sure the house has walls as well.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>193</int>
        <en>Two people will not live in the same home. Also, if their home is destroyed, they will look for a new place to live.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>194</int>
        <en>You can use the housing interface to assign and view housing. Open you inventory and click the house icon.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>195</int>
        <en>If you want a merchant to move in, you will need to gather plenty of money. 50 silver coins should do the trick!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>196</int>
        <en>For a nurse to move in, you might want to increase your maximum life.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>197</int>
        <en>If you had a gun, I bet an arms dealer might show up to sell you some ammo!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>198</int>
        <en>You should prove yourself by defeating a strong monster. That will get the attention of a dryad.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>199</int>
        <en>Make sure to explore the dungeon thoroughly. There may be prisoners held deep within.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>200</int>
        <en>Perhaps the old man by the dungeon would like to join us now that his curse has been lifted.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>201</int>
        <en>Hang on to any bombs you might find. A demolitionist may want to have a look at them.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>202</int>
        <en>Are goblins really so different from us that we couldn't live together peacefully?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>203</int>
        <en>I heard there was a powerfully wizard who lives in these parts.  Make sure to keep an eye out for him next time you go underground.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>204</int>
        <en>If you combine lenses at a demon altar, you might be able to find a way to summon a powerful monster. You will want to wait until night before using it, though.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>205</int>
        <en>You can create worm bait with rotten chunks and vile powder. Make sure you are in a corrupt area before using it.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>206</int>
        <en>Demonic altars can usually be found in the corruption. You will need to be near them to craft some items.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>207</int>
        <en>You can make a grappling hook from a hook and 3 chains. Skeletons found deep underground usually carry hooks, and chains can be made from iron bars.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>208</int>
        <en>If you see a pot, be sure to smash it open. They contain all sorts of useful supplies.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>209</int>
        <en>There is treasure hidden all over the world. Some amazing things can be found deep underground!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>210</int>
        <en>Smashing a shadow orb will sometimes cause a meteor to fall out of the sky. Shadow orbs can usually be found in the chasms around corrupt areas.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>211</int>
        <en>You should focus on gathering more heart crystals to increase your maximum life.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>212</int>
        <en>Your current equipment simply won't do. You need to make better armor.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>213</int>
        <en>I think you are ready for your first major battle. Gather some lenses from the eyeballs at night and take them to a demon altar.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>214</int>
        <en>You will want to increase your life before facing your next challenge. Fifteen hearts should be enough.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>215</int>
        <en>The ebonstone in the corruption can be purified using some powder from a dryad, or it can be destroyed with explosives.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>216</int>
        <en>Your next step should be to explore the corrupt chasms.  Find and destroy any shadow orb you find.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>217</int>
        <en>There is a old dungeon not far from here. Now would be a good time to go check it out.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>218</int>
        <en>You should make an attempt to max out your available life. Try to gather twenty hearts.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>219</int>
        <en>There are many treasures to be discovered in the jungle, if you are willing to dig deep enough.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>220</int>
        <en>The underworld is made of a material called hellstone. It's perfect for making weapons and armor.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>221</int>
        <en>When you are ready to challenge the keeper of the underworld, you will have to make a living sacrifice. Everything you need for it can be found in the underworld.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>222</int>
        <en>Make sure to smash any demon altar you can find. Something good is bound to happen if you do!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>223</int>
        <en>Souls can sometimes be gathered from fallen creatures in places of extreme light or dark.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>224</int>
        <en>Ho ho ho, and a bottle of... Egg Nog!</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>225</int>
        <en>Care to bake me some cookies?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>226</int>
        <en>What? You thought I wasn't real?</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>227</int>
        <en>I managed to sew your face back on. Be more careful next time.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>228</int>
        <en>That's probably going to leave a scar.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>229</int>
        <en>All better. I don't want to see you jumping off anymore cliffs.</en>
      </dialog>
      <dialog>
        <int>230</int>
        <en>That didn't hurt too bad, now did it?</en>
      </dialog>
    </dialogs>
  </lang>
</language>